## Danyang Zhuo

Assistant Professor Department of Computer Science Trinity College of Arts and Sciences Duke University December 6, 2021
308 Research Dr
Durham, NC 27705
danyang@cs.duke.edu
https://danyangzhuo.com

### **Research Interests**

I do research broadly in computer systems, including operating systems, distributed systems, and computer networks, with a focus on the design and implementation of data center systems to support today's increasingly data-intensive applications (e.g., deep learning, big data analytics, packet processing). My approaches include software architecture design, programming languages, and machine learning.

#### Education

University of Washington – Seattle

Seattle, Washington

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering

Sep 2013 - Aug 2019

- Dissertation: Practical, Efficient, and Reliable Data Center Communication.
- Advisors: Thomas E. Anderson, Arvind Krishnamurthy

University of Illinois - Urbana Champaign

B.S. in Electrical Engineering

Urbana, Illinois Aug 2009 - May 2013

Advisor: Nitin Vaidya

## **Professional Experience**

**Duke University**Assistant Professor of Computer Science

University of California – Berkeley

 $Postdoctoral\ Researcher$ 

– Advisor: Ion Stoica

Microsoft Research

Contractor (through Populous Group)

Microsoft Research

Research Intern

Google

Software Development Engineering Intern

Amazon

Software Development Engineering Intern

Microsoft

• Software Development Engineering Intern

Durham, North Carolina

Jul 2020 - now

Berkeley, California Sep 2019 - Jun 2020

Redmond, Washington Oct 2015 - Feb 2017

Redmond, Washington

Jun 2015 - Sep 2015

Mountain View, California Sep 2014 - Mar 2015

Seattle, Washington

May 2013 - Sep 2013

Redmond, Washington

May 2012 - Aug 2012

#### **Awards**

Meta Research Award	2021
Amazon Research Award	2021
IBM Academic Award	2021
FAST Best Paper Award	2021
University of Washington Madrona Prize Runner-Up	2018
University of Washington Hacherl Endowed Fellowship	2014
Rank 146th in the William Lowell Putnam Mathematical Competition	2012

#### **Publications**

### Conference Papers

- 1. Shunhua Jiang, Yunze Man, Zhao Song, Zheng Yu, Danyang Zhuo. Fast Graph Neural Tangent Kernel via Kronecker Sketching. The 36th AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2022.
- 2. Danyang Zhuo, Kaiyuan Zhang, Zhuohan Li, Siyuan Zhuang, Stephanie Wang, Ang Chen, Ion Stoica. *Rearchitecting In-Memory Object Stores for Low Latency*. The 48th International Conference on Very Large Data Bases (VLDB), 2022.
- 3. Zhuohan Li, Siyuan Zhuang, Shiyuan Guo, Danyang Zhuo, Hao Zhang, Dawn Song, Ion Stoica. TeraPipe: Token-Level Pipeline Parallelism for Training Large-Scale Language Models. The 38th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2021.
- 4. Siyuan Zhuang, Zhuohan Li, Danyang Zhuo, Stephanie Wang, Eric Liang, Robert Nishihara, Philipp Moritz, Ion Stoica. *Hoplite: Efficient and Fault-Tolerant Collective Communication for Task-Based Distributed Systems*. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2021.
- 5. Shumo Chu, Danyang Zhuo, Elaine Shi, T-H. Hubert Chan. Differentially Oblivious Database Joins: Overcoming the Worst-Case Curse of Fully Oblivious Algorithms. The 2nd Information-Theoretic Cryptography conference (ITC), 2021.
- 6. Sitan Chen, Xiaoxiao Li, Zhao Song, Danyang Zhuo. On InstaHide, Phase Retrieval, and Sparse Matrix Factorization. The 9th International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2021.
- 7. Samantha Miller, Kaiyuan Zhang, Mengqi Chen, Ryan Jennings, Ang Chen, Danyang Zhuo, Thomas Anderson. *High Velocity Kernel File Systems with Bento*. The 19th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies (FAST), 2021.

  Best Paper Award.
- 8. Lianmin Zheng, Chengfan Jia, Minmin Sun, Zhao Wu, Cody Hao Yu, Ameer Haj-Ali, Yida Wang, Jun Yang, Danyang Zhuo, Koushik Sen, Joseph E. Gonzalez, Ion Stoica. *Ansor: Generating High-Performance Tensor Programs for Deep Learning*. The 14th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI), 2020.
- 9. Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Arvind Krishnamurthy. Gallium: Automated Software Middlebox Offloading to Programmable Switches. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2020.

- 10. Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Aditya Akella, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Xi Wang. *Automated Verification of Customizable Middlebox Properties with Gravel.* The 17th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2020.
- 11. Danyang Zhuo, Kaiyuan Zhang, Yibo Zhu, Hongqiang Harry Liu, Matthew Rockett, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas Anderson. *Slim: OS Kernel Support for a Low-Overhead Container Overlay Network*. The 16th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2019.
- 12. Danyang Zhuo, Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Klaus-Tycho Förster, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. *Understanding and Mitigating Packet Corruption in Data Center Networks*. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2017.
- 13. Danyang Zhuo, Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Amar Phanishayee, Xuan Kelvin Zou, Hang Guan, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. *RAIL: A Case for Redundant Arrays of Inexpensive Links in Data Center Networks*. The 14th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2017.
- 14. Vincent Liu, Danyang Zhuo, Simon Peter, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. Subways: A Case for Redundant, Inexpensive Data Center Edge Links. The 13th International Conference on emerging Networking Experiments and Technologies (CoNEXT), 2015.

#### Workshop Papers

- 1. John Snyder, Alvin Lebeck, Danyang Zhuo. *RDMA Congestion Control: It's Only for the Compliant*. Cloud@MICRO, 2021.
- 2. Jialin Li, Samantha Miller, Danyang Zhuo, Ang Chen, Jon Howell, Thomas Anderson. *An Incremental Path Towards a Safe OS Kernel.* The 18th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS), 2021.
- 3. Samantha Miller, Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Shibin Xu, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas Anderson. *Practical Safe Linux Kernel Extensibility*. The 17th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS), 2019.
- 4. Danyang Zhuo, Qiao Zhang, Xin Yang, Vincent Liu. Canaries in the Network. The 15th ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets), 2016.
- 5. Danyang Zhuo, Qiao Zhang, Vincent Liu, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas E. Anderson. *Rack-level Congestion Control*. The 15th ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets), 2016.
- 6. Danyang Zhuo, Qiao Zhang, Dan Ports, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas E. Anderson. *Machine Fault Tolerance for Reliable Datacenter Systems*. The 5th Asia-Pacific Workshop on Systems (APSys), 2014.

### **Invited Papers**

1. Samantha Miller, Kaiyuan Zhang, Mengqi Chen, Ryan Jennings, Ang Chen, Danyang Zhuo, Thomas Anderson. *High Velocity Kernel File Systems with Bento*. USENIX ;login:, 2021.

#### **Patents**

1. Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Amar Phanishayee, Danyang Zhuo, Xuan Kelvin Zou. *Data Center Topology Having Multiple Classes of Reliability*. US Patent 20170302565A1. WIPO Patent 2017180450A1.

## **Students**

Current PhD Students: Jingrong Chen, Xinhao Kong, Yongji Wu Current Master Students: Guozhen She, Zhangzhang Yue, Wei Zhang

Current Interns: Baocheng Sun

## **Invited Talk**

• Towards Efficient Cloud Systems for Data-Intensive Applications.	
<ul> <li>Rice University</li> <li>Duke CS+ Undergraduate Summer Resarch Program</li> <li>IBM</li> </ul>	Jun 2021 Jun 2021 Feb 2021
• Towards Efficient and Reliable Data Center Systems.	
<ul> <li>Yale University</li> <li>Purdue University</li> <li>University of Virginia</li> <li>Duke University</li> <li>Rutgers University</li> <li>Microsoft Research</li> <li>Pennsylvania State University</li> <li>University of Minnesota</li> <li>Slim: OS Kernel Support for a Low-Overhead Container Overlay Network.</li> </ul>	Apr 2019 Apr 2019 Mar 2019 Mar 2019 Mar 2019 Feb 2019 Feb 2019
<ul> <li>Princeton University</li> <li>University of California - Berkeley</li> <li>USENIX NSDI</li> <li>Understanding and Mitigating Packet Corruption in Data Center Networks.</li> <li>ACM SIGCOMM</li> <li>RAIL: A Case for Redundant Arrays of Inexpensive Links in Data Center Networks</li> </ul>	J
– USENIX NSDI	

## **Teaching**

- Spring 2022: Data Center Systems (CompSci 590.04)
- Fall 2021: Introduction to Operating Systems (CompSci 310)
- Fall 2020: Advanced Operating Systems (CompSci 510)

# Service

# Program Committee

- 2022: APNET, FAST, NSDI, SIGCOMM

• 2021: CoNEXT

• 2020: SIGCOMM